■ arjo@[university].edu | 🖷 alrojo.github.io | 🖸 alrojo | 🛅 alexrosejo | 💆 @alexrosejo

Interest____

I'm interested in, and excited about, solving high impact problems with machine learning and computer science. In my work and research I have applied, and also contributed to, popular python frameworks for machine learning such as SciKit Learn, TensorFlow, Pytorch, OpenNMT, and Theano. These efforts have lead to publications, and business products for companies, in the fields of natural language processing (Q&A, Sentiment classification, Summarization, Machine Translation), Bioinformatics (Pretrained embeddings), and health technology (Wearables, CGM, Diabetes monitoring and classification). Recently, through my current role as a Ph.D. student in the Snyder lab at Stanford, I've expanded to extracting and analyzing data from wearable biomedical devices and fitness trackers. Beyond my individual contributions I enjoy building community around machine learning and supervising master students.

Education

Stanford University Stanford, California, USA

PH.D. COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep 2020 - now

· Advised by Professor Michael P. Snyder · 2020 Fulbright Scholar

Technical University of Denmark

Kongens Lyngby, Denmark

M.Sc. MATHEMATICAL MODELING AND COMPUTATION, GPA: 11.44/12.00 Sep 2014 - Dec 2016

• Nanyang Technological University, Singapore — Semester Abroad Fall 2015

· Honors program, Supervised by Professor Ole Winther

Copenhagen Business School B.Sc. Business Administration and Information Systems, GPA: 10.70/12.00

• Lincoln University, Canterbury, New Zealand — Semester Abroad Fall 2013

Frederiksberg, Denmark

Sep 2011 - Jun 2014

Experience _____

Ocean.io Copenhagen, Denmark

HEAD OF DATA SCIENCE RESEARCH Feb 2020 - est. Sep 2020

Developed a machine translation algorithm.

Technical University of Denmark

Kongens Lyngby, Denmark

RESEARCH PROJECT MANAGER Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

Supervised and conducted research with +30 students on machine learning methodology and applying deep learning to proteomics.

Salesforce Palo Alto, California, USA

DEEP LEARNING RESEARCH, INTERN Jan 2017 - Jan 2018

Research on deep learning for natural language processing, supervised by Richard Socher, PhD.

Teaching

Stanford University Co-Supervisor

RESEARCH COURSE SUPERVISION 2020-2022

Supervised 4 High School interns, 1 Undergraduate intern

Technical University of Denmark

Head TA, course responsible

DEEP LEARNING, INTRO REINFORCEMENT LEARNING, DEEP REINFORCEMENT LEARNING 2016-2019

Significant course material contributions (Deep Learning). Course responsible (Reinforcement Learning).

Co-Supervisor

MASTER THESIS AND RESEARCH COURSE SUPERVISION 2019-2021

Supervised 13 M.Sc. Thesis' and 11 research course projects

Community_

Deep Learning Copenhagen MeetUp

LEAD ORGANIZER

Nov. 2018 - Dec. 2019

Inspired by Stanford's public poster exam in CS224N in 2017 I convinced Professor Ole Winther to do the same for our 02456 Deep Learning course. With student posters, company sponsored first prize, drinks, and pizza. Given the positive feedback, I was hired by the university, started a research lab for students, and kept hosting events to celebrate the students projects. This was a lot of fun and resulted in seven events, +1.5k participants, and multiple company sponsorships. (Event page: meetup.com/Deep-Learning-DTU/).

Community research Online

LEAD ORGANIZER

Jan. 2020 - now

I help independent researchers who wants to pursue graduate studies and provide free supervision and problem statements to help them publish papers and get recognized. This brings me much joy, and five of my previous students are now pursuing PhDs.

Open Source

GOOGLE TENSORFLOW

contrib.seq2seq: #4761, #4686, #4382

TensorFlow tutorial (2k stars): github.com/alrojo/tensorflow-tutorial

Academic Reviews

2022	NeurIPS , Neural Information Processing Systems	Reviewer
2020-22	ICLR, International Conference on Learning Representations	Program committee
2021	PNAS, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America	Assisted review
2021	Bioinformatics,	Reviewer
2020	ACL , Association for Computational Linguistics	Reviewer
2020-21	AAAI , Association for the advancement of artificial intelligence	Program committee
2018-20	CoNLL , Computational Natural Language Learning	Reviewer

Publications

2022	Nucleic Acids Research , DeepLoc 2.0: multi-label subcellular localization prediction using protein language	Journal	
	<i>models</i> . V. Thumuluri, J. Armenteros, <u>A. Johansen</u> , H. Nielsen, O. Winther		
	Nature Biotechnology , SignalP 6.0 achieves signal peptide prediction across all types using protein language		
2022	models. F. Teufel, J. Armenteros, <u>A. Johansen</u> , M. Gíslason, S. Pihl, K. Tsirigos, O. Winther, S. Brunak, G.	Journal	
	Heijne, H. Nielsen		
2021	Bioinformatics , NetSolP: predicting protein solubility in E. coli using language models. V. Thumuluri, H.	Journal	
2021	Martiny, J. Armenteros, J. Salomon, H. Nielsen, <u>A. Johansen</u>		
2021	Computational Biology and Chemistry, Deep protein representations enable recombinant protein	1	
2021	expression prediction. H. Martiny, J. Armenteros, <u>A. Johansen</u> , J. Salomon, H. Nielsen	Journal	
2020	Current Research in Biotechnology, Prediction of GPI-Anchored proteins with pointer neural networks. M.	Journal	
2020	Gíslason, H. Nielsen, J. Armenteros, <u>A. Johansen</u>		
2020	IEEE EMBC , Short term blood glucose prediction based on continuous glucose monitoring data. A. Mohebbi,	Poster	
2020	A. Johansen, N. Hansen, P. Christensen, J. Tarp, M. Jensen, H. Bengtsson, M. Mørup	Poster	
2020	ICLR, Neural arithmetic units. A. Madsen, <u>A. Johansen</u>	Spotlight	
2017	Bioninformatics , An introduction to deep learning on biological sequence data: examples and solutions. V.	Journal	
2017	Jurtz, <u>A. Johansen</u> , M. Nielsen, J. Armenteros, H. Nielsen, C. Sønderby, O. Winther, S. Sønderby	Journal	
2017	ACM BCB, Deep recurrent conditional random field for protein secondary structure prediction. A. Johansen, C.	Oral	
	Sønderby, S. Sønderby, O. Winther	Orai	
2017	IEEE EMBC , A deep learning approach to adherence detection for type 2 diabetics. A. Mohebbi, T. Aradóttir,	Doctor	
2017	A. Johansen, H. Bengtsson, M. Fraccaro, M. Mørup	Poster	
2016	IEEE ASSP , Epileptiform spike detection via convolutional neural networks. A. Johansen, J. Jin, T. Maszczyk, J.	D - 1	
	Dauwels, S. Cash, M. Westover	Poster	

Patents_

2017	US Patent App. 15/853,530 , <i>Probability-Based Guider</i> . <u>A. Johansen</u> , B. McCann, J. Bradbury, R. Socher	Pending
2022	US Patent 11250311 , Deep Neural Network-Based Decision Network. A. Johansen, B. McCann, J. Bradbury, R.	Approved
2022	Socher	Approveu